prep4usmle.com 2016-01-26

# Prep4USMLE.com: Privacy Policy

### PRIVACY AND SECURITY POLICY

This Privacy and Security Policy is provided for the benefit of existing and prospective customers of www.prep4usmle.com (“Website”) provided by Prep for USMLE, as well as other consumers and parties who seek information from or about the Website and/or Prep for USMLE. Please read this Privacy and Security Policy carefully.

### 1\. OPENING STATEMENTS

**1.1 Prep for USMLE**  
This Privacy and Security Policy governs the privacy and security practices of Prep for USMLE and its website www.prep4usmle.com.

**1.2 Applicability of Privacy and Security Policy**  
Our Privacy and Security Policy applies to all individuals and entities from whom or for the benefit of whom we receive personally identifiable information (also commonly referred to as personally identifying information) (“PII”), whether the PII be collected through our websites; traditional mailing and/or faxing channels; telephone or electronic communications; from some other medium; or from our customers.

**1.3 Our Commitment to Privacy**  
At Prep for USMLE, we respect the privacy and the confidentiality of our customers’ PII and financial information. We are committed to keeping confidential the PII and financial information you share with us. We promise to use PII and financial information only for the purpose for which it has been collected. This Privacy and Security Policy explains how Prep for USMLE collects, uses, discloses and protects the information we obtain.

### 2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED AND HOW IT IS USED

**2.1 Personally Identifiable Information** (PII) is any information that would, by itself, identify you or tend to identify you as a particular individual or entity. This personally identifiable information may include, but not be limited to, your name, your address, credit card number, bank account information, and/or personal identification number (such as a social security number or driver’s license number).

> 2.1.1 Personally identifiable information does not include any public information that is readily attainable through federal, state or local public record distribution channels.
> 
> 2.1.2 Personally identifiable information does not include any information that, by itself, could not identify you as a particular individual or entity.
> 
> 2.1.3 Personally identifiable information also does not include raw data that becomes aggregated for statistical purposes and cannot, thereafter, be identified with you as a unique individual or entity.

**2.2 Information Collected**

> 2.2.1 Prep for USMLE collects information that is considered PII and other information that, by itself, would not be considered personally identifiable information.
> 
> 2.2.2 Typically, Prep for USMLE limits the PII collected about an individual or entity to the individual’s or entity’s name and electronic mail (“e-mail”) address.

**2.3 Collecting and Using Personal Information**

> 2.3.1 Prep for USMLE will explain how it intends to use your personally identifiable information either before it collects the information (such as in this Privacy and Security Policy) or contemporaneously with the solicitation of such information about you. Exceptions may exist where the intended use is obvious to a reasonable person.
> 
> 2.3.2 We will use the information collected only for the purposes explained to you. Further, we limit the collection of personally identifiable information to only that information which is necessary for the purposes explained to you.
> 
> 2.3.3 Unless we are required to do so by law, we shall not obtain your consent before collecting personal identifying information about you from parties other than Prep for USMLE. Rather, Prep for USMLE shall presume that you have previously provided such consent to any such third party from whom Prep for USMLE obtains such information.
> 
> 2.3.4 Prep for USMLE restricts the use of your PII to Prep for USMLE’s personnel.
> 
> 2.3.5 We shall not sell your PII in the normal course of business operations. Should the Website be sold, this paragraph shall not restrict the transfer of your PII as part of the Website sold to a third party.
> 
> 2.3.5. We may use your e-mail or regular mail address to send you communications about your transactions and our company as well as to notify you of relevant product news, new products and services, or other information that we believe may be of interest to you. If you do not wish to receive electronic communications unrelated to your transactions with Prep for USMLE, you may “opt out” of the electronic distributions upon receipt of any such communication. To discontinue receipt of email communications, you can change preferences in your [Profile Controls](http://www.prep4usmle.com/profile.php?action=editprofile).
> 
> 2.3.6. At the time of registration, Prep for USMLE allows, but does not require, you to provide additional information such as any “instant messaging” handles, a brief biography of yourself, or links to your website(s). _Please be advised that this information is visible to other Prep for USMLE consumers_.

**2.4 Disclosing Personal Information**

> 2.4.1 _General_. Prep for USMLE may provide your personally identifiable information to other persons, but only where we have your consent or where we have obtained information about you from a third party (presuming that you have previously provided such consent to any such third party from whom Prep for USMLE obtains such information) or where we are required or permitted to do so by law.
> 
> 2.4.2 
> 
> _Strategic Partners_. Prep for USMLE may employ, engage or retain certain trusted third parties (“Strategic Partners”) to perform functions and/or provide services on its behalf. Prep for USMLE will share PII with these strategic partners only to the extent necessary to perform the functions and/or provide the services for which they have been employed, engaged or retained. Prep for USMLE shall also secure contractual obligations from our strategic partners to maintain the privacy and security of the PII shared with them.
> 
> 2.4.3 
> 
> _Business Transfers_. Prep for USMLE reserves the right to sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your PII, in connection with a sale of assets; a merger, acquisition, or reorganization; or, filing for bankruptcy. You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if the planned processing of your information by the purchaser differs materially from that set forth in this Privacy and Security Policy.
> 
> 2.4.4 
> 
> _Legal Compliance_. Prep for USMLE may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims or legal process (including subpoenas); to protect the property and rights of Prep for USMLE, its strategic partners or other third parties; to protect the safety of the public or any person; to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity; or, generally, to comply with the law.

**2.5 Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

> 2.5.1 In addition to collecting personally identifiable information as previously described, Prep for USMLE also collects other non-personally identifiable information (“non-PII”).
> 
> 2.5.2 Non-PII collected by Prep for USMLE may be utilized without restriction.
> 
> 2.5.3 Although non-PII can be used in a number of ways, you can be assured that the use of the non-PII cannot identify you as an individual or entity.
> 
> 2.5.4 Because non-PII cannot be used to identify you, Prep for USMLE may in its discretion provide non-PII to other persons.

**2.6. Information Obtained From Use of Prep for USMLE’ Websites**

> 2.6.1. _Cookies_
>
>> 2.6.1.1. Cookies can be defined as bits of data stored on your computer that allow our website(s) to identify your browser and session.
>> 
>> 2.6.1.2. Prep for USMLE presently utilizes “Cookies”.
>> 
>> 2.6.1.3. Cookies allow us to recognize certain information about you in an effort to provide an extra layer of security protection against unauthorized users.
>> 
>> Based upon your web browser’s security settings, you have the ability to reject all cookies.
>> 
>> 2.6.1.4. Unfortunately, disabling or rejecting Cookies may alter your Prep for USMLE experience.
> 
> 2.6.2. _IP Addresses_
>
>> 2.6.2.1. Prep for USMLE maintains a log of your IP address when you access www.prep4usmle.com. This IP address by itself does not allow us to collect additional information about you. However, it allows us to see which parts of the site you visit and how much time you spend browsing the site.
>> 
>> 2.6.2.2. OTHER THAN YOUR IP ADDRESS, PREP FOR USMLE DOES NOT DIRECTLY COLLECT ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU UNLESS YOU VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE US WITH THIS INFORMATION OR PLACE A FORMAL REQUEST FOR SERVICES ONLINE.

**2.7 Data Retention**

> 2.7.1. The length of time for which Prep for USMLE retains your PII and other information will vary depending on the nature of the services for which the information had been collected and the nature of the information.
> 
> 2.7.2. Although this period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with Prep for USMLE, it will be retained for only so long as necessary for Prep for USMLE to respond to any issues arising from your relationship with Prep for USMLE.
> 
> 2.7.3. When Prep for USMLE no longer needs or requires your personal information, Prep for USMLE will destroy, delete, erase or convert information to an anonymous form.
> 
> 2.7.4. As all purchases from Prep for USMLE are made through third-party service providers, Prep for USMLE does not possess or retain your financial information.

### 3\. CONSENT

> 3.1. Prep for USMLE may obtain your personal information through a variety of sources. For each source or method, the manner of consent may differ.
> 
> 3.2. In general, Prep for USMLE operates on an “Opt-out” basis. That is, Prep for USMLE presumes that by accessing this website you have read this Privacy and Security Policy and Prep for USMLE’s Terms and Conditions. Moreover, by providing the personal information requested (both personally identifiable and nonpersonally identifiable), you have consented to its use by Prep for USMLE for the stated purposes.
> 
> 3.3. For these reasons, unless and until you expressly inform Prep for USMLE you do not wish your information to be used, Prep for USMLE shall presume it has your consent.
> 
> 3.4. Where Prep for USMLE obtains information about a consumer from its customers or other third parties, Prep for USMLE presumes that the consumer has previously provided appropriate consent to the party from whom Prep for USMLE obtains the information. In any case, the consumer can be assured that this Privacy and Security Policy applies to any information obtained from a third party.

### 4\. ACCESS

> 4.1. Subject to certain limitations imposed by applicable privacy laws, you may request that Prep for USMLE provide you with a copy of your personal information and/or information regarding how we have used that personal information.
> 
> 4.2. Any such requests for such information should be submitted via our [Contact Form](http://www.prep4usmle.com/contactform.php).
> 
> 4.3. We will make every effort to respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe.

### 5\. SECURITY

> 5.1. Prep for USMLE recognizes that it is essential that all data be protected and takes the issue of protecting your personal information very seriously. Prep for USMLE protects the information it obtains about you with appropriate safeguards and security measures consistent with international information practices. These measures include technical and procedural steps to protect your data from misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, loss, alteration, or destruction. While we disclose below some of these measures in general terms, we neither identify all of the measures employed nor all of the information related to such measures as part of our security protocol.
> 
> 5.2. Again, for security purposes, Prep for USMLE does not disclose all of its security measures. Be assured that Prep for USMLE does employ industry standard measures to protect your information.

### 6\. DISCLAIMER AS TO THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES

> Although www.prep4usmle.com may contain links to other third-party websites, Prep for USMLE is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites and specifically disclaims any such responsibility. Prep for USMLE does not monitor the privacy practices or content of these websites. If you have any questions about the privacy practices of a website other than a Prep for USMLE owned website, you need to contact the Privacy Officer of the website about which you have a question.

### 7\. REVISIONS TO PRIVACY AND SECURITY POLICY

> 7.1. Prep for USMLE reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this Privacy and Security Policy, our Terms of Use, and other online policies and agreements at any time and in any manner.
> 
> 7.2. Prep for USMLE shall provide notice of such changes by posting the revised policies to the applicable Prep for USMLE owned websites, in addition to sending notice as provided and/or required by law.
> 
> 7.3. With respect to this Privacy and Security Policy, you should visit our website at www.prep4usmle.com from time to time to review the then-current terms. At any time, the current-posted policies govern and shall be binding.

* If you have additional questions or concerns regarding how Prep for USMLE is managing or using your personal information, please send us your concerns via the [Contact Form](http://www.prep4usmle.com/contactform.php).

Copyright @ Prep for USMLE. All rights reserved.
